Hi friends, I am Bejoy Varghese, welcome back
to Financial Serve. Today is a
comparison video.
We are comparing two top plans in India.
ICI Lombard's
Elevate plan and Manipal
Cigna's Sarva plan. The
reason for comparing these two plans is that both
plans have a lot of riders.
Many people say that
policies with inbuilt features are very
good, but that is not the case.
Policies with more riders are very good because
we only pay for what we need. It is
like making a cake. It
only has the ingredients we need and
we
can also avoid the unnecessary ones. Manipal Sills Sarva plan
has three variants. Uttam
Parampratham is
a variant that covers criticality.
So I am not going to
discuss it here today. What are the
differences and similarities between these plans?
This is a  Just a
comparison video is all you need to know
about this product in detail. If you want to
know more about this product, I will give you the
link of the video I made about it in the description
box below. You can
watch and understand. The main USB or unique selling point that makes the ICICL
Embed Elevate plan
stand out is the
Power
Booster Rider. According to this, your
sum insured will double every year and will double
every year.
It is also unlimited. In
normal
policies, it is up to five times or
10 times.
But here it is infinite. The
second USB is the
inbuilt CIBIL discount. If
you have a good CIBIL score,
you can get up to 15% discount on the premium through this
policy. The third
USB is Infinite Care. According to this, it is
a scheme where you get the amount of claim regardless of how many lakhs of rupees you have taken a policy of Rs.
10 lakhs. For example, a
person who took a policy of Rs. 80
lakhs got a claim of Rs.
Suppose the company gives
Rs 80 lakh to that customer without any deduction,
but the important thing to note here is that
this
can be used only once. The fourth
USB is inflation protection. According to this,
your sum
assured will also increase according to inflation. The important USB of Manipal Signal Sarva
Plan is
called Anant Cover. According to this, if
any criticality is
caught,
you will get an infinite sum assured. The second
USB is called
Talkal Benefit. According to this,
you will get coverage from day one. The
third is Gulak
Benefit. According to this, your
sum assured will
increase up to 10 times. Here I have
only mentioned the important points. Let us understand in more detail. Let's
go to the
[Music]
screen. First, let's
look at the room eligibility in both the plans. In
both the plans, a single private AC room
comes as inbuilt, but in
both the plans, you
can modify your room if you want. You can
reduce or increase the room facility.
Accordingly, the premium will also
differ.  Next, let's
look at the age. In ICICI Elevate plan,
people from 18 years of age can join. There is no maximum age limit. People from 91 days to 30 years of age are considered as children.
Similarly, in Manipal
Signal Surva plan, people from 18 years of age
can join. There is
no maximum age limit here either. People from 91 days to
30 years of age are
considered as children.
Let's check the sum insured of both the policies. In
Elevate plan, you
can take a policy starting from Rs. 5 lakhs,
but there is no limit on how much money you get in this plan,
i.e. it is unlimited. In
Manipal Signal Surva plan, the
sum insured is from Rs. 5 lakhs to Rs. 3 crores. The
premium of both the policies can be paid for a period of one year, two years, three years. If you pay
the premium for two years and three years together, you get a
long-term discount on both the policies.
Next, let's check the
bonus available in these plans. In
Elevate plan, the
maximum bonus per year is 20%.  Up to 100% is
available in this way in Manipal
Signus Sarva plan. This can
be chosen as a rider. Next is Day
Care Treatment. Day
Care Treatment is available in both policies. It is covered up to Sum Insured.
Next is Domiciliary Hospitalization.
This is also available in both policies. It is covered up to Sum Insured. Next is Ayush. Ayush is available in
both policies. It is covered up to Sum Insured.
Ayush means Ayurveda,
Yoga, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy.
Next is Refill Benefit
or Restoration Benefit.
Unlimited Times
Refill Benefit is available in ICICI Elevate plan.
This can be chosen as a rider in Manipal Signa Uttam plan. In
Param plan, 100%
Sum Insured is available. It can be used for related
and unrelated diseases.
Now let's take the emergency road.  Let
's look at the ambulance. Both policies are covered up to the sum
assured. Next is the
emergency air ambulance. This is a
rider that we
can choose in both policies. Next is the
complimentary wellness test. This is a
rider that we can choose in the Elevate plan. This is also a rider that we can choose in the Manipal Singhna Uttam plan. However, it is
inbuilt in the Param plan.
This can be used once a year.
Next is the wellness benefit. In the ICICI
Elevate plan, we get up to 30% wellness
benefit. In the Manipal
Signal Sarva plan, we get up to 20% wellness
benefit. For this, we
can use the Wealthy app. Now let's
look at the pre and post hospitalization of both policies. In both
policies, pre-hospitalization is
90 days and post-
hospitalization is 180 days.
Pre-hospitalization is the period of 90 days
before we are admitted to the hospital.  If it
is said that it is post-hospitalization, then
the bills that
can be claimed for 180 days after discharge from the hospital are next. This consultation can be
chosen as a rider in the Elevate plan. This consultation is available as an inbuilt unlimited rider in the Serva plan. Next is Consumables cover.
Consumables rider can
be chosen in both the plans. Next is Modern
treatment. Modern
treatment is covered in both the plans.
Robotic surgery is also available in both the plans. Next is
OPD cover.
This can be chosen as a rider in the Elevate plan. This is not
available in the Serva plan. Next is Deductible.
Deductible option is not available in the Elevate plan. However, in
Manipal Cigna Serva
plan, this can be chosen as a rider.
However, if you
want to opt for this in the Elevate plan,
you
can choose the co-payment option. Next is Maternity.
Maternity expenses can be chosen as a rider in the Elevate plan.
Newborn baby
cover is also available.  Along with this, you can
choose maternity coverage and newborn baby coverage as riders in Manipal Cigna Uttam plan. This is how you get 20% of the sum insured
or a maximum of Rs. 5 lakh.
Maternity benefit is not available in Manipal Cigna Param plan.
Global coverage is not
available in both the plans. We can only
improve future videos through your feedback.
So if
you
have understood the things so far, comment as Clear
or C for easy. If
you do not
understand anymore,
comment as Not Clear or NC for easy.
Similarly, if you write the time of the part you do not understand
as a comment,
I will immediately add a comment explaining it.
Now let's take a look at the
waiting periods of both the plans.
Like all normal policies, the coverage for illnesses starts after the first 30 days,
but the coverage for accidents starts from day one. The
next is the
Specified Illness Waiting Period. In
Elevate plan, there are two  The
waiting period for Specified Illness is one year,
similarly in Uttam plan, the
waiting period for Specified Illness is two years. There is no waiting period in Param plan.
Next is the PD or Pre-existing Disease waiting period. There is a
three-year waiting period for your current illnesses in Elevate plan and Uttam plan.
There is no waiting period in Param plan. Now let's
take a look at the riders in these plans. I had
said earlier that what makes both these plans
beautiful is the riders. There are about
eighteen riders available in Elevate plan. There are about
thirteen riders available in Uttam plan. There are also
eight riders available in Param plan. If
you want to understand these in detail,
I have made an individual video. I am giving their link in the
description.
You can watch and understand.
I had said that there are mainly 18 riders in Elevate plan. Let me tell you what
they are.
First of all,  Durable Medical
Equipment Second Dependent
Accommodation Benefit Third Annual
Health Checkup Fourth Claim
Protector Fifth Power
Booster Sixth Infinite Care Seventh
Domestic Air Ambulance Cover Eighth
Network Advantage Ninth
Nursing at Home Tenth Compassionate Visit Eleventh
Inflation Protector Twelfth Convalescence Expense Thirteenth
Critical Illness
Cover Fourteenth Personal Accident Fifteenth Jump Start Sixteenth
Room Modifier Seventeenth
Co-payment
Eighteenth Be Fit or OPD
Now let's take a
look at the riders of the Uttam plan. The
first rider in the Uttam plan is called the Annual
Health Checkup.  The second is Anant
Cover i.e. Infinite Cover for
Listed Illnesses, the third is
Maternity and Newborn Baby
Hospitalization Expense,
the fourth is Restoration of Sum
Insured, the fifth is Gulla Cover, the sixth is
Sarathi Benefit, the
seventh is Surplus Benefit, the eighth is
Personal Accident Cover, the
ninth is Coverage for Non-Medical
Expenses, the tenth is Air Ambulance
Coverage, the eleventh is Room Rent
Modification, the twelfth
is Elderly Co-payment, and the thirteenth
is Deductibles. Now let us
see what are the riders in Param Plan. The
first rider in Param Plan is
Hope, the second rider
is Surplus Benefit, the third is
Personal Accident Cover, and the fourth is
Coverage for Non-Medical Expenses.  The
sixth is air ambulance, the
sixth is room print modification, the seventh is
elderly co-payment, and the eighth is
deductible. I have explained all these
in detail in our individual
videos. I do not want to waste
time. If
you want to
know more about any of these riders, you can
watch the individual video. Now let's
look at an example of the premium. I say this in every video.
Premium examples are
never accurate
because the
premium
varies according to the age of each person. Here I have given the premium for Elevate
Plan, Uttam Plan, Param
Plan, and a 31-year-old man with his
wife and child taking a policy.
You can see and
understand. If you want to
know your premium, you can
contact my WhatsApp number 9495530858. Many people
sometimes comment after watching the video that the
premium chart was not
included. I have
said this in many videos because the
old  Unlike policies, many current
policies have riders,
so
calculating the premium and making a chart is a
very practical and
difficult task. That's why
I told you to WhatsApp if you want to
know your premium correctly.
One thing you should know is that exclusions are the most common exclusions.
Circumcision, suicide attempt, unproven treatment, cosmetic treatment, congenital external disease,
alcoholism, drugs, nutritional deficiency,
internal self-injury, contact
lenses, hearing aids, beauty treatment,
plastic
surgery, danger spots,
etc. There will be
minor changes in these depending on each company. To
know more, you can
look at the terms of the policies. I will tell you two more things to
keep in mind while taking health insurance.
First, you can only get a claim if you are admitted to the hospital for at least
24 hours. If you are
admitted,  Not only that, there must have been some
treatment there.
This does not apply to day care.
Secondly, if you are
admitted to the hospital, you must register your claim within 24 hours.
Health
insurance changes from time to time.
I have prepared this video for educational purposes.
Sometimes mistakes may occur. If
you know more about this policy, if you want to
add any point or
correct any mistake, comment below this video.
But it will be
beneficial for everyone. It would be better if you read its brochure and voting
before taking any policy.
Due to lack of time, not all
points are fully
explained in the video. Similarly, you
should understand which diseases are specified and which are exclusions.
You should also know the waiting period, sub-limit, co-payment of the policy. If you want to
know more about this, I am giving the link to the
video I made earlier about this in the
I card above and in the
description box below.
You
can see that at some point
when the claim was rejected,
I did not know anything about this and no
one told me.  There is
no point in saying that I didn't tell you anything. This video
ends here. If you are watching this video
on YouTube,
subscribe to the Financial Serv channel and
enable the bell icon next to it. If you are
watching it on Facebook, like the Financial Survey page and
follow Financial Survey's Instagram ID. Only then will you receive notifications of
new videos that I upload. If
you need brochures,
pricing, premium charts, etc. of products, you
can join Financial Survey's WhatsApp Telegram channels. Then, until you see a new
topic and a new video,
sign off. Have a nice day.